<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.2 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.2 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.2</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/whats-new-in-3-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/whats-new-in-3-2/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.2. ArangoDB 3.2 also contains several bugfixes that are not listed here.
Storage engines ArangoDB 3.2 offers two storage engines:
the always-existing memory-mapped files storage engine a new storage engine based on RocksDB&amp;nbsp; Memory-mapped files storage engine (MMFiles) The former storage engine (named MMFiles engine henceforth) persists data in memory-mapped files.
Any data changes are done first in the engine&amp;rsquo;s write-ahead log (WAL).</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.2</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/known-issues-in-3-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/known-issues-in-3-2/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
RocksDB storage engine The RocksDB storage engine is intentionally missing the following features that are present in the MMFiles engine:
the datafile debugger (arango-dfdb) cannot be used with this storage engine
RocksDB has its own crash recovery so using the dfdb will not make any sense here.
APIs that return collection properties or figures will return slightly different attributes for the RocksDB engine than for the MMFiles engine.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.2</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/incompatible-changes-in-3-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.2/incompatible-changes-in-3-2/</guid><description>AQL AQL breaking change in cluster: The SHORTEST_PATH statement using edge-collection names instead of a graph name now requires to explicitly name the vertex-collection names within the AQL query in the cluster. It can be done by adding WITH &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; at the beginning of the query.
Example:
FOR v,e IN OUTBOUND SHORTEST_PATH @start TO @target edges [...] Now has to be:
WITH vertices FOR v,e IN OUTBOUND SHORTEST_PATH @start TO @target edges [.</description></item></channel></rss>