<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OS-specific Information on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/</link><description>Recent content in OS-specific Information on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading on Linux</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/linux/</guid><description>By installing the new ArangoDB package the standalone instance is automatically upgraded. In addition to the ArangoDB daemon (arangod), also the ArangoDB Starter binary is updated. As a result, the procedure described below is a first step to upgrade more complex deployments such as a Cluster or an Active Failover setup.
It is highly recommended to take a backup of your data before upgrading ArangoDB using arangodump. Upgrading via APT (Ubuntu) First add the repository key to apt:</description></item><item><title>Upgrading on macOS</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/macos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/macos/</guid><description>If you installed ArangoDB on macOS using a DMG package for a single server installation, follow the instructions below to upgrade the deployment.
It is highly recommended to take a backup of your data before upgrading ArangoDB using arangodump. Upgrading via Package Download&amp;nbsp; the latest ArangoDB macOS package and install it as usual by mounting the .dmg file. Drag and drop the ArangoDB3-CLI (Community Edition) or the ArangoDB3e-CLI (Enterprise Edition) file onto the shown Applications folder.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading on Windows</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/upgrading/os-specific-information/windows/</guid><description>As there are different ways to install ArangoDB on Windows, the upgrade method depends on the installation method that was used.
In general, it will be needed to:
Install (or unpack) the new ArangoDB binaries on the system Upgrade the current database (or perform a restore) Optional (but suggested) to keep the system clean (unless there are specific reasons to not do so): remove the old binaries from the system Some of the above steps may be done automatically, depending on your specific situation.</description></item></channel></rss>