<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SmartGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/</link><description>Recent content in SmartGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started with SmartGraphs</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/getting-started/</guid><description>SmartGraphs cannot use existing collections. When switching to SmartGraph from an existing dataset you have to import the data into a fresh SmartGraph.
All collections that are being used in SmartGraphs need to be part of the same distributeShardslike group. The smartGraphAttribute and the number of shards are immutable. The smartGraphAttribute attribute is used to inform the database how to shard data and, as a consequence, all vertices must have this attribute.</description></item><item><title>SmartGraph Management</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/management/</guid><description>This chapter describes the JavaScript interface for creating and modifying SmartGraphs. A SmartGraph is a specialized version of a General Graph, which means all of the General Graph functionality is available on a SmartGraph as well. The major difference of both modules is handling of the underlying collections:
General Graphs do not enforce or maintain any sharding of the collections and can therefore combine arbitrary sets of existing collections. SmartGraphs enforce and rely on a special sharding of the underlying collections and hence can only work with collections that are created through the SmartGraph itself.</description></item><item><title>SmartGraphs and SatelliteGraphs on a Single Server</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/testing-graphs-on-single-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/smartgraphs/testing-graphs-on-single-server/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition ArangoGraph General idea You can create SmartGraphs and SatelliteGraphs in a single server instance and test them there. Internally, the graphs are General Graphs, supplemented by formal properties such as isSmart, which play no role in the behavior of the graphs, however. The same is true for vertex and edge collections: they have the corresponding properties, but they are non-functional.
After a test phase, you can dump such graphs and then restore them in a cluster instance.</description></item></channel></rss>