<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.3 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.3 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.3</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/whats-new-in-3-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/whats-new-in-3-3/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.3. ArangoDB 3.3 also contains several bugfixes that are not listed here.
Datacenter-to-datacenter replication (DC2DC) Every company needs a disaster recovery plan for all important systems. This is true from small units like single processes running in some container to the largest distributed architectures. For databases in particular this usually involves a mixture of fault-tolerance, redundancy, regular backups and emergency plans.</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.3</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/known-issues-in-3-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/known-issues-in-3-3/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
Issue Date Added: 2018-12-04 Component: arangod Deployment Mode: All Description: Parallel creation of collections using multiple client connections with the same database user may spuriously fail with &amp;ldquo;Could not update user due to conflict&amp;rdquo; warnings when setting user permissions on the new collections. A follow-up effect of this may be that access to the just-created collection is denied. Affected Versions: 3.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.3</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/incompatible-changes-in-3-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.3/incompatible-changes-in-3-3/</guid><description>AQL: during a traversal if a vertex is not found, arangod will not log an error and continue with a NULL value, but will instead register a warning at the query and continue with a NULL value.
If a non-existing vertex is referenced from a traversal, it is not desirable to log errors as ArangoDB can store edges pointing to non-existing vertices (which is perfectly valid if the low-level insert APIs are used).</description></item></channel></rss>