<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Official ArangoDB drivers on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/</link><description>Recent content in Official ArangoDB drivers on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArangoDB Java driver</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/java/</guid><description>The official ArangoDB Java Driver.
Repository: https://github.com/arangodb/arangodb-java-driver&amp;nbsp; Code examples&amp;nbsp; Reference (driver setup, serialization, changes in version 7) JavaDoc&amp;nbsp; (generated reference documentation) ChangeLog&amp;nbsp; Supported versions Version 7 is the latest supported and actively developed release.
The driver is compatible with all supported stable versions of ArangoDB server, see Product Support End-of-life Announcements&amp;nbsp;.
The driver is compatible with JDK 8 and higher versions.
Version 6 reached End of Life (EOL) and is not actively developed anymore.</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Go driver</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/go/</guid><description>The official Go driver in version 2 is the recommended client for interacting with ArangoDB using the Go programming language.
Reference: https://pkg.go.dev/github.com/arangodb/go-driver/v2&amp;nbsp; Repository: https://github.com/arangodb/go-driver/tree/master/v2&amp;nbsp; Changelog&amp;nbsp; Tutorial Install the driver To use the driver, fetch the sources into your GOPATH first.
go get github.com/arangodb/go-driver/v2 Import the driver in your Go program using the import statement. Two packages are necessary:
import ( &amp;#34;github.com/arangodb/go-driver/v2/arangodb&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/arangodb/go-driver/v2/connection&amp;#34; ) You may want to additionally import the following packages:</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB JavaScript driver</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/javascript/</guid><description>The official ArangoDB low-level JavaScript client.
Repository: https://github.com/arangodb/arangojs&amp;nbsp; Reference: http://arangodb.github.io/arangojs/&amp;nbsp; Changelog&amp;nbsp; If you are looking for the ArangoDB JavaScript API in Foxx&amp;nbsp; or the arangosh interactive shell, please refer to the documentation about the @arangodb module instead.
The JavaScript driver is only meant to be used when accessing ArangoDB from outside the database.
Compatibility The arangojs driver is compatible with the latest stable version of ArangoDB available at the time of the driver release and remains compatible with the two most recent Node.</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Python driver</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/drivers/python/</guid><description>The Python-Arango driver is the recommended driver for using ArangoDB as the database backend from Python. It is maintained by ArangoDB and the community.
Repository: https://github.com/ArangoDB-Community/python-arango&amp;nbsp; Reference: https://docs.python-arango.com/&amp;nbsp; Tutorial&amp;nbsp; Releases&amp;nbsp; Installation The python-arango library can be used in any Python project that targets Python version 3.8 or later.
To install the library using PIP, run the following command in a terminal:
pip install python-arango --upgrade You can then import the library in your project as follows:</description></item></channel></rss>