<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Graph Analytics</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/graph-analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/graph-analytics/</guid><description>Graph analytics is a branch of data science that deals with analyzing information networks known as graphs, and extracting information from the data relationships. It ranges from basic measures that characterize graphs, over PageRank, to complex algorithms. Common use cases include fraud detection, recommender systems, and network flow analysis.
ArangoDB offers a feature for running algorithms on your graph data, called Graph Analytics Engines (GAEs). It is available on request for the ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;.</description></item><item><title>ArangoGraphML</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/</guid><description>Traditional machine learning overlooks the connections and relationships between data points, which is where graph machine learning excels. However, accessibility to GraphML has been limited to sizable enterprises equipped with specialized teams of data scientists. ArangoGraphML, on the other hand, simplifies the utilization of GraphML, enabling a broader range of personas to extract profound insights from their data.
How GraphML works GraphML focuses on the utilization of neural networks specifically for graph-related tasks.</description></item><item><title>ArangoGraph Notebooks</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangograph-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangograph-notebooks/</guid><description>ArangoGraph Notebooks don&amp;rsquo;t include the ArangoGraphML services. To enable the ArangoGraphML services, get in touch&amp;nbsp; with the ArangoDB team. The ArangoGraph Notebook is a JupyterLab notebook embedded in the ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;. The notebook integrates seamlessly with the platform, automatically connecting to ArangoGraph services and ArangoDB. This makes it much easier to leverage these resources without having to download any data locally or to remember user IDs, passwords, and endpoint URLs.</description></item><item><title>Large Language Models (LLMs) and Knowledge Graphs</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/llm-knowledge-graphs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/llm-knowledge-graphs/</guid><description>Large language models (LLMs) and knowledge graphs are two prominent and contrasting concepts, each possessing unique characteristics and functionalities that significantly impact the methods we employ to extract valuable insights from constantly expanding and complex datasets.
LLMs, exemplified by OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s ChatGPT, represent a class of powerful language transformers. These models leverage advanced neural networks to exhibit a remarkable proficiency in understanding, generating, and participating in contextually-aware conversations.
On the other hand, knowledge graphs contain carefully structured data and are designed to capture intricate relationships among discrete and seemingly unrelated information.</description></item><item><title>Adapters</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/</guid><description>ArangoDB Adapters provide a convenient way to integrate ArangoDB with popular data science tools. By enabling you to to use your preferred programming languages and libraries, these adapters simplify the data analysis process and make it easier to leverage the power of ArangoDB in data science.
Read more about the adapters available in ArangoDB:
NetworkX cuGraph PyTorch Geometric (PyG) Deep Graph Library (DGL) Resource Description Framework (RDF)</description></item></channel></rss>