<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The ArangoGraph API on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/</link><description>Recent content in The ArangoGraph API on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get started with the ArangoGraph API</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/set-up-a-connection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/set-up-a-connection/</guid><description>The instructions below are a quick start guide on how to set up a connection to the ArangoGraph API.
All examples below will use the Go programming language. Since the ArangoGraph API is using gRPC with protocol buffers, all examples can be easily translated to many different languages.
Prerequisites Make sure that you have already signed up for ArangoGraph&amp;nbsp;.
Creating an API key Go to dashboard.arangodb.cloud&amp;nbsp; and login. Click the user icon in the top-right of the dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Get started with the ArangoGraph API and Oasisctl</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/get-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/api/get-started/</guid><description>This tutorial shows you how to do the following:
Generate an API key and authenticate with Oasisctl View information related to your organizations, projects, and deployments Configure, create and delete a deployment With Oasisctl the general command structure is to execute commands such as:
oasisctl list deployments This command lists all deployments available to the authenticated user and we will explore it in more detail later. Most commands also have associated --flags that are required or provide additional options, this aligns with the interaction method for many command line utilities.</description></item></channel></rss>