<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EnterpriseGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/</link><description>Recent content in EnterpriseGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with EnterpriseGraphs</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/getting-started/</guid><description>EnterpriseGraphs cannot use existing collections. When switching to EnterpriseGraph from an existing dataset, you have to import the data into a fresh EnterpriseGraph.
When creating an EnterpriseGraph, you cannot have different number of shards per collection. To preserve the sharding pattern, the _from and _to attributes of the edges cannot be modified. You can define any _key value on vertices, including existing ones.
Migrating from Community Edition When migrating from the Community Edition to the Enterprise Edition, you can bring data from existing collections using the command-line tools arangoexport and arangoimport.</description></item><item><title>EnterpriseGraphs Management</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/graphs/enterprisegraphs/management/</guid><description>An EnterpriseGraph is a specialized version of a SmartGraph, which means that both modules work similarly. The major difference is that EnterpriseGraphs rely on a special automated sharding of the underlying collections and hence can only work with collections that are created through the EnterpriseGraph itself. EnterpriseGraphs cannot overlap.
To generally understand the concept of this module please read the chapter about General Graph Management first, and continue with SmartGraph Management.</description></item></channel></rss>