<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Load your data into ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/</link><description>Recent content in Load your data into ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Add files into Data Loader</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/add-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/add-files/</guid><description>The Data Loader allows you to upload your data files in CSV format into ArangoGraph and then use these data sources to design a graph using the built-in graph designer.
Upload your files You can upload your CSV files in the following ways:
Drag and drop your files in the designated area. Click the Browse files button and select the files you want to add. You have the option to either upload several files collectively as a batch or add them individually.</description></item><item><title>Design your graph</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/design-graph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/design-graph/</guid><description>Based on the data you have uploaded, you can start designing your graph. The graph designer allows you to create a schema using nodes and edges. Once this is done, you can save and start the import. The resulting EnterpriseGraph and the corresponding collections are created in your ArangoDB database instance.
How to add a node Nodes are the main objects in your data model and include the attributes of the objects.</description></item><item><title>Start the import</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/import/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/import/</guid><description>Before starting the actual import, make sure that:
You have selected a database for import or created a new one; You have provided a valid name for your graph; You have created at least one node; You have created at least one edge; You have uploaded at least one file; Every file is related to at least one node or edge; Every node and edge is linked to a file; Every node and edge has a unique label; Every node has a primary identifier selected; Every edge has an origin and destination file header selected.</description></item><item><title>Data Loader Example</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/arangograph/data-loader/example/</guid><description>To transform your data into a graph, you need to have CSV files with entities representing the nodes and a corresponding CSV file representing the edges.
This example uses a sample data set of two files, airports.csv, and flights.csv. These files are used to create a graph showing flights arriving at and departing from various cities. You can download the files from GitHub&amp;nbsp;.
The airports.csv contains rows of airport entries, which are the future nodes in your graph.</description></item></channel></rss>