<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SatelliteGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/</link><description>Recent content in SatelliteGraphs on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SatelliteGraph Management</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/management/</guid><description>This chapter describes the satellite-graph module, the JavaScript API to create and modify your SatelliteGraphs in ArangoDB.
To generally understand the concept of the graph modules please see General Graph Management first. In the following only the overloaded functionality is described. Everything else works alike in both modules.
Create a Graph In contrast to General Graphs and SmartGraphs, you do not need to take care of the sharding and replication properties.</description></item><item><title>SatelliteGraph Details</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/details/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/graphs/satellitegraphs/details/</guid><description>Below you find usage examples and advanced configuration possibilities for SatelliteGraphs. The examples use arangosh and the @arangodb/satellite-graph module. You can also manage SatelliteGraphs via the HTTP API.
How to create a SatelliteGraph SatelliteGraphs enforce and rely on special properties of the underlying collections and hence can only work with collections that are either created implicitly through the SatelliteGraph interface, or manually with the correct properties:
There needs to be a prototype collection with replicationFactor set to &amp;quot;satellite&amp;quot; All other collections need to have distributeShardsLike set to the name of the prototype collection Collections can be part of multiple SatelliteGraphs.</description></item></channel></rss>