<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organizations in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/</link><description>Recent content in Organizations in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Users and Groups in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/users-and-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/users-and-groups/</guid><description>Users, groups &amp;amp; members When you use ArangoGraph, you are logged in as a user. A user has properties such as name &amp;amp; email address. Most important of the user is that it serves as an identity of a person.
A user is member of one or more organizations in ArangoGraph. You can become a member of an organization in the following ways:
Create a new organization. You will become the first member and owner of that organization.</description></item><item><title>Billing in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/billing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/billing/</guid><description>How to add billing details In the main navigation menu, click the Organization icon. Click Billing in the Organization section. In the Billing Details section, click Edit. Enter your company name, billing address, and EU VAT identification number (if applicable). Optionally, enter the email address(es) to which invoices should be emailed to automatically. Click Save. How to add a payment method In the main navigation menu, click the Organization icon.</description></item><item><title>Credits &amp; Usage in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/credits-and-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/credits-and-usage/</guid><description>Credits are only available if your organization has signed up for ArangoGraph&amp;rsquo;s Committed package. The ArangoGraph credit model is a versatile prepaid model that allows you to purchase credits and use them in a flexible way, based on what you have running in ArangoGraph.
Instead of purchasing a particular deployment for a year, you can purchase a number of ArangoGraph credits that expire a year after purchase. These credits are then consumed over that time period, based on the deployments you run in ArangoGraph.</description></item></channel></rss>