<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ArangoGraph Insights Platform on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/</link><description>Recent content in ArangoGraph Insights Platform on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Organizations in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/organizations/</guid><description>An ArangoGraph organizations is a container for projects. An organization typically represents a (commercial) entity such as a company, a company division, an institution, or a non-profit organization.
Organizations → Projects → Deployments
Users can be members of one or more organizations. However, you can only be a member of one Free-to-try tier organization at a time.
How to switch between my organizations The first entry in the main navigation (with a double arrow icon) indicates the current organization.</description></item><item><title>Projects in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/projects/</guid><description>ArangoGraph projects can represent organizational units such as teams, product groups, environments (e.g. staging vs. production). You can have any number of projects under one organization.
Organizations → Projects → Deployments
Projects are a container for related deployments, certificates &amp;amp; IP allowlists. Projects also come with their own policy for access control. You can have any number of deployment under one project.
How to create a new project In the main navigation, click the Dashboard icon.</description></item><item><title>Deployments in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/</guid><description>An ArangoGraph deployment is an ArangoDB cluster or single server, configured as you choose.
Each deployment belongs to a project, which belongs to an organization in turn. You can have any number of deployments under one project.
Organizations → Projects → Deployments
How to create a new deployment If you do not have a project yet, create a project first. In the main navigation, click Deployments. Click the New deployment button.</description></item><item><title>Load your data into ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/data-loader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/data-loader/</guid><description>ArangoGraph provides different ways of loading your data into the platform, based on your migration use case.
Transform data into a graph The ArangoGraph Data Loader allows you to transform existing data from CSV file formats into data that can be analyzed by the ArangoGraph platform.
You provide your data in CSV format, a common format used for exports of data from various systems. Then, using a no-code editor, you can model the schema of this data and the relationships between them.</description></item><item><title>ArangoGraph Notebooks</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/notebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/notebooks/</guid><description>This documentation describes the beta version of the Notebooks feature and is subject to change. The beta version is free for all. The ArangoGraph Notebook is a JupyterLab notebook embedded in the ArangoGraph Insights Platform. The notebook integrates seamlessly with platform, automatically connecting to ArangoGraph services, including ArangoDB and the ArangoML platform services. This makes it much easier to leverage these resources without having to download any data locally or to remember user IDs, passwords, and endpoint URLs.</description></item><item><title>My Account in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/my-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/my-account/</guid><description>You can access information related to your account via the User Toolbar. The toolbar is in the top right corner in the ArangoGraph dashboard and accessible from every view. There are two elements:
Question mark icon: Help User icon: My Account Overview How to view my account Hover over or click the user icon of the User Toolbar in the top right corner. Click Overview in the My account section. The Overview displays your name, email address, company and when the account was created.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring &amp; Metrics in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/monitoring-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/monitoring-and-metrics/</guid><description>The ArangoGraph Insights Platform provides integrated charts, metrics, and logs to help you monitor your deployment. This allows you to track your deployment&amp;rsquo;s performance, resource utilization, and its overall status.
The key features include:
Built-in monitoring: Get immediate access to monitoring capabilities for your deployments without any additional setup. Chart-based metrics representation: Visualize the usage of the DB-Servers and Coordinators over a selected timeframe. Integration with Prometheus and Grafana: Connect your metrics to Prometheus and Grafana for in-depth visualization and analysis.</description></item><item><title>Security and access control in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/security-and-access-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/security-and-access-control/</guid><description>The ArangoGraph Insights Platform has a structured set of resources that are subject to security and access control:
Organizations Projects Deployments For each of these resources, you can perform various operations. For example, you can create a project in an organization and create a deployment inside a project.
Locked resources In ArangoGraph, you can lock the resources to prevent accidental deletion. When a resource is locked, it cannot be deleted and must be unlocked first.</description></item><item><title>Backups in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/backups/</guid><description>How to create backups To backup data in ArangoGraph for an ArangoDB installation, navigate to the Backups section of your deployment created previously.
There are two ways to create backups. Create periodic backups using a Backup policy, or create a backup manually. Both ways allow you to create backups in multiple regions as well.
Periodic backups Periodic backups are created at a given schedule. To see when the new backup is due, observe the schedule section.</description></item><item><title>The ArangoGraph API</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/api/</guid><description>The ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;, comes with its own API. This API enables you to control all resources inside ArangoGraph in a scriptable manner. Typical use cases are spinning up ArangoGraph deployments during continuous integration and infrastructure as code.
The ArangoGraph API…
is a well-specified API that uses Protocol Buffers&amp;nbsp; as interface definition and gRPC&amp;nbsp; as underlying protocol.
allows for automatic generation of clients for a large list of languages. A Go client is available out of the box.</description></item><item><title>Oasisctl</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/oasisctl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/oasisctl/</guid><description>Oasisctl is a command-line tool for using the ArangoGraph API. This tool makes integration of ArangoGraph in all kinds of (bash) scripts easy. It is also a good example on how to use the API.
See Getting started with Oasisctl for a tutorial.
Oasisctl is available for Linux, macOS and Windows. Download and source code:
github.com/arangodb-managed/oasisctl&amp;nbsp;</description></item></channel></rss>