<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security and access control in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/</link><description>Recent content in Security and access control in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>X.509 Certificates in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/x-509-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/x-509-certificates/</guid><description>X.509 certificates are digital certificates that are used to verify the authenticity of a website, user, or organization using a public key infrastructure (PKI). They are used in various applications, including SSL/TLS encryption, which is the basis for HTTPS - the primary protocol for securing communication and data transfer over a network.
The X.509 certificate format is a standard defined by the International Telecommunication Union (ITU)&amp;nbsp; and contains information such as the name of the certificate holder, the public key associated with the certificate, the certificate&amp;rsquo;s issuer, and the certificate&amp;rsquo;s expiration date.</description></item><item><title>Single Sign-On (SSO) in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/single-sign-on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/security-and-access-control/single-sign-on/</guid><description>To enable the Single Sign-On (SSO) feature, get in touch with the ArangoGraph team via Request Help, available in the left sidebar menu of the ArangoGraph Dashboard. About SAML 2.0 The Security Assertion Markup language 2.0 (SAML 2.0) is an open standard created to provide cross-domain single sign-on (SSO). It allows you to authenticate in multiple web applications by using a single set of login credentials.
SAML SSO works by transferring user authentication data from the identity provider (IdP) to the service provider (SP) through an exchange of digitally signed XML documents.</description></item></channel></rss>