<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.5 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.5 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.5</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/whats-new-in-3-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/whats-new-in-3-5/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.5. ArangoDB 3.5 also contains several bug fixes that are not listed here.
ArangoSearch Configurable Analyzers Analyzers can split string values into smaller parts and perform additional processing such as word stemming and case conversion. In ArangoDB 3.4 there is a fixed set of text analyzers for 12 different languages, which tokenize strings into case-insensitive word stems using language-dependent rules based on the chosen locale, without discarding any stop-words (common words which carry little meaning such as &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.5</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/known-issues-in-3-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/known-issues-in-3-5/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
ArangoSearch Issue Date Added: 2018-12-19 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Single-server Description: Value of _id attribute indexed by ArangoSearch view may become inconsistent after renaming a collection Affected Versions: 3.5.x Fixed in Versions: - Reference: arangodb/backlog#514&amp;nbsp; (internal) Date Added: 2018-12-03 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Cluster Description: Score values evaluated by corresponding score functions (BM25/TFIDF) may differ in single-server and cluster with a collection having more than 1 shard Affected Versions: 3.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.5</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/incompatible-changes-in-3-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.5/incompatible-changes-in-3-5/</guid><description>ID values in log messages By default, ArangoDB and its client tools now show a 5 digit unique ID value in any of their log messages, e.g.
2019-03-25T21:23:19Z [8144] INFO [cf3f4] ArangoDB (version 3.5.0 enterprise [linux]) is ready for business. Have fun!. In this message, the cf3f4 is the message&amp;rsquo;s unique ID value. ArangoDB users can use this ID to build custom monitoring or alerting based on specific log ID values.</description></item></channel></rss>