<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.1 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.1 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.1</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/whats-new-in-3-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/whats-new-in-3-1/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.1. ArangoDB 3.1 also contains several bugfixes that are not listed here.
SmartGraphs ArangoDB 3.1 adds a first major Enterprise Edition feature called SmartGraphs. SmartGraphs form an addition to the already existing graph features and allow to scale graphs beyond a single machine while keeping almost the same query performance. The SmartGraph feature is suggested for all graph database use cases that require a cluster of DB-Servers for what ever reason.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.1</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/incompatible-changes-in-3-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/version-3.1/incompatible-changes-in-3-1/</guid><description>Communication Layer The internal communication layer is now based on Boost ASIO. A few options regarding threads and communication have been changed.
There are no longer two different threads pools (--scheduler.threads and --server.threads). The option --scheduler.threads has been removed. The number of threads is now controlled by the option --server.threads only. By default --server.threads is set to the number of hyper-cores.
As a consequence of the change, the following (hidden) startup options have been removed:</description></item></channel></rss>