<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Features and Capabilities on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features and Capabilities on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community Edition Features</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/community-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/community-edition/</guid><description>The Community Edition features are outlined below. For additional information, see arangodb.com/community-server/&amp;nbsp;.
General Graph Database: Native support for storing and querying graphs comprised of vertices and edges. You can model complex domains because edges are documents without any restrictions in complexity.
Document Database: A modern document database system that allows you to model data intuitively and evolve the data model easily. Documents can be organized in collections, and collections in databases for multi-tenancy.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Edition Features</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/enterprise-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/enterprise-edition/</guid><description>The Enterprise Edition has all the features of the Community Edition and, on top of that, the features outlined below. For additional information, see arangodb.com/enterprise-server/&amp;nbsp;.
Performance SmartGraphs: Value-based sharding of large graph datasets for better data locality when traversing graphs.
EnterpriseGraphs: A specialized version of SmartGraphs, with an automatic sharding key selection.
SmartGraphs using SatelliteCollections: Collections replicated on all cluster nodes can be combined with graphs sharded by document attributes to enable more local execution of graph queries.</description></item><item><title>Highlights by Version</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/highlights-by-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/highlights-by-version/</guid><description>Version 3.12 All Editions
Improved memory accounting: Better tracking and observability of memory consumption for ArangoDB deployments and reduced memory usage.
wildcard Analyzer: Accelerate LIKE searches with _ and % wildcards against Views and inverted indexes with n-grams to quickly find candidate matches.
Multi-dimensional indexes: An index type to efficiently intersect multiple range queries, like finding all appointments that intersect a time range. Optionally with prefix fields, with support for using it as vertex-centric index in graph traversals.</description></item></channel></rss>