<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HTTP interfaces related to monitoring on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/</link><description>Recent content in HTTP interfaces related to monitoring on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTTP interface for server logs</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/logs/</guid><description>Whether events are logged to a file, syslog, or only an attached terminal depends on the log startup options.
See Log levels for a detailed description of the FATAL, ERROR, and other levels of log messages.
The permissions required to use the /_admin/log* endpoints depends on the setting of the --log.api-enabled startup option.
Get the global server logs GET /_admin/log/entries Returns fatal, error, warning or info log messages from the server&amp;rsquo;s global log.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for server statistics</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/statistics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/statistics/</guid><description>Get the statistics GET /_db/{database-name}/_admin/statistics This endpoint should no longer be used. It is deprecated from version 3.8.0 on. Use /_admin/metrics/v2 instead, which provides the data exposed by this API and a lot more. Returns the statistics information. The returned object contains the statistics figures grouped together according to the description returned by /_admin/statistics-description. For instance, to access a figure userTime from the group system, you first select the sub-object describing the group stored in system and in that sub-object the value for userTime is stored in the attribute of the same name.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for server metrics</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/http-api/monitoring/metrics/</guid><description>arangod exports metrics in the Prometheus format&amp;nbsp;. The thresholds for alerts are described for relevant metrics.
The list of exposed metrics is subject to change in every minor version. While they should stay backwards compatible for the most part, some metrics are coupled to specific internals that may be replaced by other mechanisms in the future. Whether the /_admin/metrics* endpoints are available depends on the setting of the --server.export-metrics-api startup option.</description></item></channel></rss>