<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.4 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.4 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.4</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/whats-new-in-3-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/whats-new-in-3-4/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.4. ArangoDB 3.4 also contains several bug fixes that are not listed here.
ArangoSearch ArangoSearch is a sophisticated, integrated full-text search solution over a user-defined set of attributes and collections. It is the first type of view in ArangoDB.
ArangoSearch tutorial&amp;nbsp; ArangoSearch overview ArangoSearch in AQL: SEARCH operation ArangoSearch functions New geo index implementation S2 based geo index The geo index in ArangoDB has been reimplemented based on S2 library&amp;nbsp; functionality.</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.4</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/known-issues-in-3-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/known-issues-in-3-4/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
ArangoSearch Issue Date Added: 2018-12-03 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Cluster Description: Score values evaluated by corresponding score functions (BM25/TFIDF) may differ in single-server and cluster with a collection having more than 1 shard Affected Versions: 3.4.x, 3.5.x Fixed in Versions: - Reference: arangodb/backlog#508&amp;nbsp; (internal) Date Added: 2018-12-03 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Cluster Description: ArangoSearch index consolidation does not work during creation of a link on existing collection which may lead to massive file descriptors consumption Affected Versions: 3.</description></item><item><title>Deprecated features</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/incompatible-changes-in-3-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.4/incompatible-changes-in-3-4/</guid><description>Release packages The official ArangoDB release packages for Linux are now built as static executables linked with the musl libc&amp;nbsp; standard library. For Linux, there are release packages for the Debian-based family of Linux distributions (.deb), and packages for RedHat-based distributions (.rpm). There are no specialized binaries for the individual Linux distributions nor for their individual subversions.
The release packages are intended to be reasonably portable (see minimum supported architectures below) and should run on a variety of different Linux distributions and versions.</description></item></channel></rss>