<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HTTP interface for indexes on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/</link><description>Recent content in HTTP interface for indexes on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTTP interface for persistent indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/persistent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/persistent/</guid><description>The index types hash and skiplist are aliases for the persistent index type and should no longer be used to create new indexes. The aliases will be removed in a future version. Create a persistent index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index Creates a persistent index for the collection collection-name, if it does not already exist. The call expects an object containing the index details.
In a sparse index all documents will be excluded from the index that do not contain at least one of the specified index attributes (i.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for inverted indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/inverted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/inverted/</guid><description>Create an inverted index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index Creates an inverted index for the collection collection-name, if it does not already exist. The call expects an object containing the index details. Path Parameters database-name* string The name of the database.
Query Parameters collection* string The collection name.
HTTP Headers Request Body application/json object analyzer string The name of an Analyzer to use by default. This Analyzer is applied to the values of the indexed fields for which you don&amp;rsquo;t define Analyzers explicitly.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for TTL (time-to-live) indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/ttl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/ttl/</guid><description>Create a TTL index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index Creates a time-to-live (TTL) index for the collection collection-name if it does not already exist. The call expects an object containing the index details. Path Parameters database-name* string The name of the database.
Query Parameters collection* string The collection name.
HTTP Headers Request Body application/json object expireAfter* number The time interval (in seconds) from the point in time stored in the fields attribute after which the documents count as expired.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for multi-dimensional indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/multi-dimensional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/multi-dimensional/</guid><description>Create a multi-dimensional index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index Creates a multi-dimensional index for the collection collection-name, if it does not already exist. The call expects an object containing the index details. Path Parameters database-name* string The name of the database.
Query Parameters collection* string The collection name.
HTTP Headers Request Body application/json object estimates boolean (default: true) This attribute controls whether index selectivity estimates are maintained for the index. Not maintaining index selectivity estimates can have a slightly positive impact on write performance.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for geo-spatial indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/geo-spatial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/geo-spatial/</guid><description>Create a geo-spatial index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index Creates a geo-spatial index in the collection collection, if it does not already exist. Expects an object containing the index details.
Geo indexes are always sparse, meaning that documents that do not contain the index attributes or have non-numeric values in the index attributes will not be indexed.
Path Parameters database-name* string The name of the database.
Query Parameters collection* string The collection name.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for full-text indexes</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/fulltext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/develop/http-api/indexes/fulltext/</guid><description>Create a full-text index POST /_db/{database-name}/_api/index The fulltext index type is deprecated from version 3.10 onwards. Creates a fulltext index for the collection collection-name, if it does not already exist. The call expects an object containing the index details. Path Parameters database-name* string The name of the database.
Query Parameters collection* string The collection name.
HTTP Headers Request Body application/json object fields* array of strings an array of attribute names.</description></item></channel></rss>