<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deployments in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/</link><description>Recent content in Deployments in ArangoGraph on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Private endpoint deployments in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/private-endpoints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/private-endpoints/</guid><description>This topic describes how to create a private endpoint deployment and securely deploy to various cloud providers such as Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Microsoft Azure, and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Follow the steps outlined below to get started.
Private endpoints on Microsoft Azure can be cross region; in AWS they should be located in the same region. For more information about the certificates used for private endpoints, please refer to the How to manage certificates section.</description></item><item><title>Upgrades and Versioning in ArangoGraph</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/upgrades-and-versioning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/arangograph/deployments/upgrades-and-versioning/</guid><description>Please note that this policy comes into effect in April 2023. Release Definitions The following definitions are used for release types of ArangoDB within ArangoGraph:
Release Introduces Contains breaking changes Major (X.y.z) Major new features and functionalities Likely large changes Minor (x.Y.z) Some new features or improvements Likely small changes Patch (x.y.Z) Essential fixes and improvements Small changes in exceptional circumstances Release Channels When creating a deployment in ArangoGraph, you can select the minor version of ArangoDB that your deployment is going to use.</description></item></channel></rss>