<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get Started on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/</link><description>Recent content in Get Started on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/get-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use ArangoDB in the Cloud</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/set-up-a-cloud-instance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/set-up-a-cloud-instance/</guid><description>For general information about the ArangoGraph Insights Platform, see dashboard.arangodb.cloud&amp;nbsp;.
For guides and reference documentation, see the ArangoGraph documentation.
Prerequisites Please have following information at hand for registration:
An email address, required for email verification. If you use a public email service provider (e.g. Hotmail), make sure to have the following information at hand as well:
A mobile phone number, required for SMS verification One mobile phone number is associated with one account and cannot be used for multiple accounts.</description></item><item><title>Install ArangoDB on-premises</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/on-premises-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/on-premises-installation/</guid><description>Installation Head to arangodb.com/download&amp;nbsp;, select your operating system, and download ArangoDB. You may also follow the instructions on how to install with a package manager, if available.
If you installed a binary package under Linux, the server is automatically started.
For more in-depth information on how to install ArangoDB, as well as available startup parameters, installation in a cluster and so on, see Installation and Deploy.
Securing the Installation The default installation contains one database _system and a user named root.</description></item><item><title>How to Interact With ArangoDB</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/how-to-interact-with-arangodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/how-to-interact-with-arangodb/</guid><description>How to Communicate with the Server The core component of ArangoDB is the ArangoDB server (arangod) that stores data and handles requests. You have different options for talking to the server, through the web interface, command-line tools, drivers, and the server&amp;rsquo;s REST API.
Web Interface The easiest way to get started with ArangoDB is to use the included web interface. The ArangoDB server serves this graphical user interface (GUI) and you can access it by pointing your browser to the server&amp;rsquo;s endpoint, which is http://localhost:8529 by default if you run a local server.</description></item><item><title>Start using AQL</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/start-using-aql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/get-started/start-using-aql/</guid><description>This is an introduction to ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s query language AQL, built around a small dataset of characters from the novel and fantasy drama television series Game of Thrones (as of season 1). It includes character traits in two languages, some family relations, and last but not least a small set of filming locations, which makes for an interesting mix of data to work with.
There is no need to import the data before you start.</description></item></channel></rss>