<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documents on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/</link><description>Recent content in Documents on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schema Validation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/schema-validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/schema-validation/</guid><description>While ArangoDB is schema-less, it allows to enforce certain document structures on the collection level. The desired structure can be described in the popular JSON Schema&amp;nbsp; format (draft-4, without support for remote schemas for security reasons). The level of validation and a custom error message can be configured. The system attributes _key, _id, _rev, _from and _to are ignored by the schema validation.
Enable schema validation for a collection Schema validation can be managed via the JavaScript API, typically using arangosh, as well as via the HTTP interface.</description></item><item><title>Computed Values</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/computed-values/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/concepts/data-structure/documents/computed-values/</guid><description>Introduced in: v3.10.0
If you want to add default values to new documents, maintain auxiliary attributes for search queries, or similar, you can set these attributes manually in every operation that inserts or modifies documents. However, it is more convenient and reliable to let the database system take care of it.
The computed values feature lets you define expressions on the collection level that run on inserts, modifications, or both. You can access the data of the current document to compute new values using a subset of AQL.</description></item></channel></rss>