<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cluster deployments on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/</link><description>Recent content in Cluster deployments on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cluster Deployment</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/deployment/</guid><description>You can deploy an ArangoDB cluster in different ways:
Using the ArangoDB Starter Manual Start Kubernetes ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;, fully managed, available on AWS, Azure &amp;amp; GCP Preliminary Information For Debian/Ubuntu Systems Use a different configuration file for the Cluster instance The configuration file used for the standalone instance is /etc/arangodb3/arangod.conf (on Linux), and you should use a different one for the cluster instance(s). If you are using the Starter binary arangodb, that is automatically the case.</description></item><item><title>Administrate ArangoDB cluster deployments</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/administration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/administration/</guid><description>This section includes information related to the administration of an ArangoDB Cluster.
For a general introduction to the ArangoDB Cluster, please refer to the Cluster chapter.
There is also a detailed Cluster Administration Course&amp;nbsp; for download.
Enabling synchronous replication For an introduction about Synchronous Replication in Cluster, please refer to the Cluster Architecture section.
You can enable synchronous replication per collection. When you create a collection, you may specify the number of replicas using the replicationFactor parameter.</description></item><item><title>Limitations of ArangoDB cluster deployments</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/limitations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/deploy/cluster/limitations/</guid><description>ArangoDB has no built-in limitations to horizontal scalability. The central resilient Agency will easily sustain hundreds of DB-Servers and Coordinators, and the usual database operations work completely decentrally and do not require assistance of the Agency.
Likewise, the supervision process in the Agency can easily deal with lots of servers, since all its activities are not performance critical.
Obviously, an ArangoDB Cluster is limited by the available resources of CPU, memory, disk and network bandwidth and latency.</description></item></channel></rss>