<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adapters on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/</link><description>Recent content in Adapters on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NetworkX Adapter</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-networkx-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-networkx-adapter/</guid><description>ArangoDB now has a closer integration with NetworkX allowing NetworkX users to persist their graphs in ArangoDB &amp;amp; leverage GPU-accelerated graph analytics via cuGraph. Learn more here&amp;nbsp;. NetworkX&amp;nbsp; is a commonly used tool for analysis of network-data. If your analytics use cases require the use of all your graph data, for example, to summarize graph structure, or answer global path traversal queries, then using the ArangoDB Pregel API is recommended.</description></item><item><title>cuGraph Adapter</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-cugraph-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-cugraph-adapter/</guid><description>ArangoDB now has a closer integration with NetworkX allowing NetworkX users to persist their graphs in ArangoDB &amp;amp; leverage GPU-accelerated graph analytics via cuGraph. Learn more here&amp;nbsp;. While offering a similar API and set of graph algorithms to NetworkX, RAPIDS cuGraph&amp;nbsp; library is GPU-based. Especially for large graphs, this results in a significant performance improvement of cuGraph compared to NetworkX. Please note that storing node attributes is currently not supported by cuGraph.</description></item><item><title>PyTorch Geometric (PyG) Adapter</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-pyg-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-pyg-adapter/</guid><description>PyTorch Geometric (PyG) is a library built upon PyTorch&amp;nbsp; to easily write and train Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) for a wide range of applications related to structured data.
It consists of various methods for deep learning on graphs and other irregular structures, also known as geometric deep learning&amp;nbsp;, from a variety of published papers. In addition, it consists of easy-to-use mini-batch loaders for operating on many small and single giant graphs, multi GPU-support&amp;nbsp;, DataPipe support&amp;nbsp;, distributed graph learning via Quiver&amp;nbsp;, a large number of common benchmark datasets (based on simple interfaces to create your own), the GraphGym&amp;nbsp; experiment manager, and helpful transforms, both for learning on arbitrary graphs as well as on 3D meshes or point clouds.</description></item><item><title>DGL Adapter</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-dgl-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-dgl-adapter/</guid><description>The Deep Graph Library (DGL)&amp;nbsp; is an easy-to-use, high performance and scalable Python package for deep learning on graphs. DGL is framework agnostic, meaning that, if a deep graph model is a component of an end-to-end application, the rest of the logics can be implemented in any major frameworks, such as PyTorch, Apache MXNet or TensorFlow.
Resources Watch this lunch &amp;amp; learn session&amp;nbsp; to get an introduction and see how to use the DGL adapter.</description></item><item><title>RDF Adapter</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-rdf-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/adapters/arangodb-rdf-adapter/</guid><description>RDF is a standard model for data interchange on the Web. RDF has features that facilitate data merging even if the underlying schemas differ, and it specifically supports the evolution of schemas over time without requiring all the data consumers to be changed.
RDF extends the linking structure of the Web to use URIs to name the relationship between things as well as the two ends of the link (this is usually referred to as a &amp;ldquo;triple&amp;rdquo;).</description></item></channel></rss>