<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ArangoGraphML on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/</link><description>Recent content in ArangoGraphML on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy ArangoGraphML</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/deploy/</guid><description>Managed cloud service versus self-managed ArangoDB offers two deployment options, tailored to suit diverse requirements and infrastructure preferences:
Managed cloud service via the ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp; Self-managed solution via the ArangoDB Kubernetes Operator&amp;nbsp; ArangoGraphML ArangoGraphML provides enterprise-ready Graph Machine Learning as a Cloud Service via Jupyter Notebooks that run on the ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;.
To get access to ArangoGraphML services and packages, get in touch&amp;nbsp; with the ArangoDB team. Accessible at all levels Low code UI Notebooks APIs Full usability MLOps lifecycle Metrics Metadata capture Model management Setup The ArangoGraphML managed-service runs on the ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with ArangoGraphML</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/arangographml/getting-started/</guid><description>ArangoGraphML provides an easy-to-use &amp;amp; scalable interface to run Graph Machine Learning on ArangoDB Data. Since all of the orchestration and ML logic is managed by ArangoGraph, all that is typically required are JSON specifications outlining individual processes to solve an ML Task. If you are using the self-managed solution, additional configurations may be required.
The arangoml is a Python Package allowing you to manage all of the necessary ArangoGraphML components, including:</description></item></channel></rss>