<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Troubleshooting on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Query debug packages</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/query-debug-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/query-debug-packages/</guid><description>Query debug packages, or debug dumps, facilitate the debugging of issues you might find after executing AQL queries. A debug package is a JSON file that contains information about the query and the environment to make it possible to reproduce the issue:
General information about the server including the exact version The properties of the involved database, collections, Views, and graphs The query, its bind variables, and options The query execution plan Storage engine statistics Optionally samples of your data, with the option to obfuscate all string values in a non-reversible way Before sharing a debug package, open the file locally and check if it contains anything that you are not allowed or willing to share and obfuscate it.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting _arangod_</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/arangod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/arangod/</guid><description>Server not starting or not reachable If the ArangoDB server does not start or if you cannot connect to it using arangosh or other clients, you can try to find the problem cause by executing the following steps. If the server starts up without problems you can skip this section.
Check the server log file: If the server has written a log file you should check it because it might contain relevant error context information.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Console</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/emergency-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/emergency-console/</guid><description>The ArangoDB database server has two modes of operation: As a server, where it will answer to client requests and as an emergency console, in which you can access the database directly. The latter - as the name suggests - should only be used in case of an emergency, for example, a corrupted collection. Using the emergency console allows you to issue all commands normally available in actions and transactions. When starting the server in emergency console mode, the server cannot handle any client requests.</description></item><item><title>Cluster Troubleshooting</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/operations/troubleshooting/cluster/</guid><description>Cluster front end is unresponsive
Check if the Coordinator(s) in question are started up. Check if the Agency is up and a leader has been elected. If not ensure that all or a majority of Agents are up and running. Check if all processes have been started up with the same JWT_SECRET. If not ensure that the JWT_SECRET used across the cluster nodes is identical for every process. Check if all cluster nodes have been started with SSL either dis- or enabled.</description></item></channel></rss>