<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.7 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.7 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.7</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/whats-new-in-3-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/whats-new-in-3-7/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.7. ArangoDB 3.7 also contains several bug fixes that are not listed here.
ArangoSearch Wildcard search ArangoSearch was extended to support the LIKE() function and LIKE operator in AQL. This allows to check whether the given search pattern is contained in specified attribute using wildcard matching (_ for any single character and % for any sequence of characters including none):</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.7</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/known-issues-in-3-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/known-issues-in-3-7/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
ArangoSearch Issue Date Added: 2018-12-19 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Single-server Description: Value of _id attribute indexed by ArangoSearch view may become inconsistent after renaming a collection Affected Versions: 3.5.x, 3.6.x, 3.7.x Fixed in Versions: - Reference: arangodb/backlog#514&amp;nbsp; (internal) Date Added: 2018-12-03 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Cluster Description: Score values evaluated by corresponding score functions (BM25/TFIDF) may differ in single-server and cluster with a collection having more than 1 shard Affected Versions: 3.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.7</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/incompatible-changes-in-3-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/incompatible-changes-in-3-7/</guid><description>MMFiles storage engine This version of ArangoDB does not contain the MMFiles storage engine anymore. In ArangoDB 3.7, the only available storage engine is the RocksDB storage engine, which is the default storage engine in ArangoDB since version 3.4. The MMFiles storage engine had been deprecated since the release of ArangoDB 3.6.
Any deployments that use the MMFiles storage engine will need to migrate to the RocksDB storage engine using ArangoDB 3.</description></item><item><title>API Changes in ArangoDB 3.7</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/api-changes-in-3-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/release-notes/version-3.7/api-changes-in-3-7/</guid><description>UTF-8 validation The ArangoDB server will now perform more strict UTF-8 string validation for incoming JSON and VelocyPack data. Attribute names or string attribute values with incorrectly encoded UTF-8 sequences will be rejected by default, and incoming requests containing such invalid data will be responded to with errors by default.
In case an ArangoDB deployment already contains UTF-8 data from previous versions, this will be a breaking change. For this case, there is the startup option --server.</description></item></channel></rss>