<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cluster Deployment on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Cluster Deployment on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Start an ArangoDB cluster manually</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/manual-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/manual-start/</guid><description>An ArangoDB Cluster consists of several running tasks or processes which form the Cluster.
This section describes how to start a Cluster by manually starting all the needed processes.
Before continuing, be sure to read the Architecture section to get a basic understanding of the underlying architecture and the involved roles in an ArangoDB Cluster.
We will include commands for a local test (all processes running on a single machine) and for a more real production scenario, which makes use of 3 different machines.</description></item><item><title>Create an ArangoDB cluster Using the ArangoDB Starter</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/using-the-arangodb-starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/cluster/deployment/using-the-arangodb-starter/</guid><description>This section describes how to start a Cluster using the Starter tool (the arangodb executable).
As a precondition you should create a secret to activate authentication. The Starter provides a handy functionality to generate such a file:
arangodb create jwt-secret --secret=arangodb.secret Set appropriate privilege on the generated secret file, e.g. on Linux:
chmod 400 arangodb.secret Also see Security for instructions of how to create certificates and tokens needed to secure an ArangoDB deployment.</description></item></channel></rss>