<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Concepts on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/</link><description>Recent content in Concepts on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Structure</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-structure/</guid><description>How Data is Structured in ArangoDB The hierarchy that data is organized in is documents (data records) in collections, and collections in databases.
Documents ArangoDB lets you store documents as JSON objects.
{ &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;ArangoDB&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;graph&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;database&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;NoSQL&amp;#34;], &amp;#34;scalable&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;company&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;ArangoDB Inc.&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;founded&amp;#34;: 2015 } } Each record that you store is a JSON object at the top-level, also referred to as a document. Each key-value pair is called an attribute, comprised of the attribute name and the attribute value.</description></item><item><title>Data Models</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-models/</guid><description>Key-Value Model The key-value data model is a subset of ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s document data model. Every document has a _key attribute that identifies a document within a collection. This document key acts as the primary key to retrieve the data. You can set it when creating a document, or let the system generate one automatically. It cannot be changed later because the attribute is immutable. It is always a string. What you can use as a document key is described in User-specified keys.</description></item><item><title>Data Retrieval</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/data-retrieval/</guid><description>Queries are used to filter documents based on certain criteria, to compute or store new data, as well as to manipulate or delete existing documents. Queries can be as simple as returning individual records, or as complex as traversing graphs or performing joins using many collections. Queries are written in the ArangoDB Query Language, AQL for short.
Cursors are used to iterate over the result of queries, so that you get easily processable batches instead of one big hunk.</description></item></channel></rss>