<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What is ArangoDB? on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/</link><description>Recent content in What is ArangoDB? on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArangoDB Use Cases</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/use-cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/use-cases/</guid><description>ArangoDB as a Graph Database ArangoDB as a graph database is a great fit for use cases like fraud detection, knowledge graphs, recommendation engines, identity and access management, network and IT operations, social media management, traffic management, and many more.
Fraud Detection Uncover illegal activities by discovering difficult-to-detect patterns. ArangoDB lets you look beyond individual data points in disparate data sources, allowing you to integrate and harmonize data to analyze activities and relationships all together, for a broader view of connection patterns, to detect complex fraudulent behavior such as fraud rings.</description></item><item><title>Features and Capabilities</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/features/</guid><description>On-premises versus Cloud Fully managed cloud service The fully managed multi-cloud ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp; is the easiest and fastest way to get started. It runs the Enterprise Edition of ArangoDB, lets you deploy clusters with just a few clicks, and is operated by a dedicated team of ArangoDB engineers day and night. You can choose from a variety of support plans to meet your needs.
Supports many of the AWS and GCP cloud deployment regions High availability featuring multi-region zone clusters, managed backups, and zero-downtime upgrades Integrated monitoring, alerting, and log management Highly secure with encryption at transit and at rest Includes elastic scalability for all deployment models (OneShard and Sharded clusters) To learn more, go to the ArangoGraph documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>