<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>_arangodump_ on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/</link><description>Recent content in _arangodump_ on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>_arangodump_ Examples</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/examples/</guid><description>arangodump can be invoked in a command line by executing the following command:
arangodump --output-directory &amp;#34;dump&amp;#34; This connects to an ArangoDB server and dump all non-system collections from the default database (_system) into an output directory named dump. Invoking arangodump fails if the output directory already exists. This is an intentional security measure to prevent you from accidentally overwriting already dumped data. If you are positive that you want to overwrite data in the output directory, you can use the parameter --overwrite true to confirm this:</description></item><item><title>_arangodump_ Options</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/options/</guid><description>arangodump Options
Usage: arangodump [&amp;lt;options&amp;gt;]
General --all-databases Type: boolean
Whether to dump all databases.
This option can be specified without a value to enable it.
--batch-size Type: uint64
The maximum size for individual data batches (in bytes).
Default: 67108864
--check-configuration Type: boolean
Check the configuration and exit.
This is a command, no value needs to be specified. The process terminates after executing the command.
--collection Type: string&amp;hellip;
Restrict the dump to this collection name (can be specified multiple times).</description></item><item><title>_arangodump_ Data Maskings</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/maskings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/maskings/</guid><description>The masking feature allows you to define how sensitive data shall be dumped. It is possible to exclude collections entirely, limit the dump to the structural information of a collection (name, indexes, sharding etc.) or to obfuscate certain fields for a dump.
You can make use of the feature by specifying a configuration file using the --maskings startup option when invoking arangodump.
A JSON configuration file is used to define which collections and fields to mask and how.</description></item><item><title>_arangodump_ Limitations</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/limitations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/arangodump/limitations/</guid><description>arangodump has the following limitations:
In a cluster, arangodump does not guarantee to dump a consistent snapshot if write operations happen while the dump is in progress (see Hot Backups for an alternative). It is therefore recommended not to perform any data-modification operations on the cluster while arangodump is running. This is in contrast to what happens on a single instance, where even if write operations are ongoing, the created dump is consistent, as a snapshot is taken when the dump starts.</description></item></channel></rss>