<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operations on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/</link><description>Recent content in Operations on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/</guid><description>To install ArangoDB, as first step, please download a package for your operating system from the official Download&amp;nbsp; page of the ArangoDB web site.
You can find packages for various operating systems, including RPM and Debian packages for Linux, including tar.gz archives. For macOS, only client tools tar.gz packages are available. For Windows, Installers and zip archives are available.
Linux macOS Windows You can also use the official Docker images&amp;nbsp; to run ArangoDB in containers on Linux, macOS, and Windows.</description></item><item><title>Backup and Restore</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/backup-and-restore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/backup-and-restore/</guid><description>ArangoDB supports three backup methods:
Physical (raw or &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo;) backups Logical backups Hot backups These backup methods save the data which is in the database system. In addition, make sure to backup things like configuration files, startup scripts, Foxx services, access tokens, secrets, certificates etc. and store them in a different location securely.
Performing frequent backups is important and a recommended best practices that can allow you to recover your data in case unexpected problems occur.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/upgrading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/upgrading/</guid><description>When upgrading from a 3.11 version, please see Resolving known issues with versions up to 3.11.11 and follow the linked upgrade procedures instead of the regular upgrade procedure. Upgrade methods There are two main ways to upgrade ArangoDB:
In-Place upgrade: when the installed ArangoDB package is replaced with a new one, and the new server executable is started on the existing data directory.
The database files typically require to be upgraded when you upgrade to a consecutive release, for example, from 3.</description></item><item><title>Administration</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/</guid><description>Tools Deployments of ArangoDB servers can be managed with the following tools:
Web interface: arangod serves a graphical web interface to be accessed with a browser via the server port. It provides basic and advanced functionality to interact with the server and its data.
ArangoShell: arangosh is a V8 shell to interact with any local or remote ArangoDB server through a JavaScript interface. It can be used to automate tasks.</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/security/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/troubleshooting/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>