<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.0 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.0 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.0</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/whats-new-in-3-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/whats-new-in-3-0/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.0. ArangoDB 3.0 also contains several bugfixes that are not listed here.
Internal data format changes ArangoDB now uses VelocyPack&amp;nbsp; for storing documents, query results and temporarily computed values. Using a single data format removed the need for some data conversions in the core that slowed operations down previously.
The VelocyPack format is also quite compact, and reduces storage space requirements for &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; values such as boolean, integers, short strings.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.0</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/incompatible-changes-in-3-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/release-notes/version-3.0/incompatible-changes-in-3-0/</guid><description>Build system Building ArangoDB 3.0 from source now requires CMake.
The pre-3.0 build system used a configure-based approach. The steps to build ArangoDB 2.8 from source code were:
make setup ./configure &amp;lt;options&amp;gt; make These steps will not work anymore, as ArangoDB 3.0 does not come with a configure script.
To build 3.0 on Linux, create a separate build directory first:
mkdir -p build and then create the initial build scripts once using CMake:</description></item></channel></rss>