<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Version 3.10 on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/</link><description>Recent content in Version 3.10 on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features and Improvements in ArangoDB 3.10</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/whats-new-in-3-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/whats-new-in-3-10/</guid><description>The following list shows in detail which features have been added or improved in ArangoDB 3.10. ArangoDB 3.10 also contains several bug fixes that are not listed here.
Native ARM Support ArangoDB is now available for the ARM architecture, in addition to the x86-64 architecture.
It can natively run on Apple silicon (e.g. M1 chips). It was already possible to run 3.8.x and older versions on these systems via Rosetta 2 emulation, but not 3.</description></item><item><title>Known Issues in ArangoDB 3.10</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/known-issues-in-3-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/known-issues-in-3-10/</guid><description>Note that this page does not list all open issues.
ArangoSearch Issue Date Added: 2018-12-19 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Single-server Description: Value of _id attribute indexed by arangosearch View may become inconsistent after renaming a collection Affected Versions: 3.5.x, 3.6.x, 3.7.x, 3.8.x, 3.9.x, 3.10.x Fixed in Versions: - Reference: arangodb/backlog#514&amp;nbsp; (internal) Date Added: 2018-12-03 Component: ArangoSearch Deployment Mode: Cluster Description: Score values evaluated by corresponding score functions (BM25/TFIDF) may differ in single-server and cluster with a collection having more than 1 shard Affected Versions: 3.</description></item><item><title>Incompatible changes in ArangoDB 3.10</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/incompatible-changes-in-3-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/incompatible-changes-in-3-10/</guid><description>Declaration of start vertex collections In cluster deployments, you need to declare collections that an AQL query implicitly reads from using the WITH operation.
From version 3.10.0 onward, it is necessary to also declare the collections of start vertices that are used for graph traversals if you specify start vertices using strings.
In previous versions, the following query would work:
WITH managers FOR v, e, p IN 1..2 OUTBOUND &amp;#39;users/1&amp;#39; usersHaveManagers RETURN { v, e, p } Now, you need to declare the users collection as well because the start vertex users/1 is specified as a string and the users collection is not otherwise specified explicitly in a language construct:</description></item><item><title>API Changes in ArangoDB 3.10</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/api-changes-in-3-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/release-notes/version-3.10/api-changes-in-3-10/</guid><description>HTTP RESTful API Behavior changes Early connections The HTTP interface of arangod instances can now optionally be started earlier during the startup process, so that ping probes from monitoring tools can already be responded to when the instance has not fully started.
By default, the HTTP interface is opened at the same point during the startup sequence as in previous versions, but it can optionally be opened earlier by setting the new --server.</description></item></channel></rss>