<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication deployment on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication deployment on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Set up ArangoDB clusters for Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangodb-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangodb-cluster/</guid><description>There are several ways to start an ArangoDB cluster. This section focuses on the recommended way to start ArangoDB: the ArangoDB Starter.
For other possibilities to deploy an ArangoDB cluster see Cluster Deployment.
The Starter simplifies things for the operator and coordinates a distributed cluster startup across several machines and assign cluster roles automatically.
When started on several machines and enough machines have joined, the Starters start Agents, Coordinators and DB-Servers on these machines.</description></item><item><title>Set up the ArangoSync Master for Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangosync-master/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangosync-master/</guid><description>The ArangoSync Master is responsible for managing all synchronization, creating tasks and assigning those to the ArangoSync Workers.
At least 2 instances must be deployed in each datacenter. One instance will be the &amp;ldquo;leader&amp;rdquo;, the other will be a &amp;ldquo;follower&amp;rdquo;. When the leader is gone for a short while, one of the other instances will take over.
With clusters of a significant size, the sync master will require a significant set of resources.</description></item><item><title>Set up the ArangoSync Workers for Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangosync-workers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/arangosync-workers/</guid><description>The ArangoSync Worker is responsible for executing synchronization tasks.
For optimal performance at least 1 worker instance must be placed on every machine that has an ArangoDB DB-Server running. This ensures that tasks can be executed with minimal network traffic outside of the machine.
Since sync workers will automatically stop once their TLS server certificate expires (which is set to 2 years by default), it is recommended to run at least 2 instances of a worker on every machine in the datacenter.</description></item><item><title>Set up Prometheus &amp; Grafana for Datacenter-to-Datacenter-Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/prometheus-and-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/prometheus-and-grafana/</guid><description>ArangoSync provides metrics in a format supported by Prometheus&amp;nbsp; that you can optionally use. ArangoDB also provides a standard set of dashboards for viewing those metrics in Grafana&amp;nbsp;.
If you want to use these tools, please refer to their websites for instructions on how to deploy them.
After deployment, you must configure Prometheus using a configuration file that instructs it about which targets to scrape. For ArangoSync you should configure scrape targets for all sync masters and all sync workers.</description></item></channel></rss>