<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HTTP interface for replication on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/</link><description>Recent content in HTTP interface for replication on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Replication dump commands</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-dump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-dump/</guid><description>Inventory The inventory method can be used to query an ArangoDB database&amp;rsquo;s current set of collections plus their indexes. Clients can use this method to get an overview of which collections are present in the database. They can use this information to either start a full or a partial synchronization of data, e.g. to initiate a backup or the incremental data synchronization.
Get a replication inventory GET /_api/replication/inventory Returns the array of collections and their indexes, and the array of Views available.</description></item><item><title>Replication logger commands</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-logger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-logger/</guid><description>All data-modification operations are written to the server&amp;rsquo;s write-ahead log and are not handled by a separate replication logger.
You can query the current state of the logger and fetch the latest changes written by the logger with the logger-state method. The operations return the state and data from the write-ahead log.
To query the latest changes logged by the replication logger, the HTTP interface also provides the logger-follow method. This method should be used by replication clients to incrementally fetch updates from an ArangoDB database.</description></item><item><title>Replication applier commands</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-applier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/replication-applier/</guid><description>The applier commands allow to remotely start, stop, and query the state and configuration of an ArangoDB database&amp;rsquo;s replication applier.
Get the replication applier configuration GET /_api/replication/applier-config Returns the configuration of the replication applier.
The body of the response is a JSON object with the configuration. The following attributes may be present in the configuration:
endpoint: the logger server to connect to (e.g. &amp;ldquo;tcp://192.168.173.13:8529&amp;rdquo;).
database: the name of the database to connect to (e.</description></item><item><title>Other Replication Commands</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/other-replication-commands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/other-replication-commands/</guid><description>Get the replication server ID GET /_api/replication/server-id Returns the servers id. The id is also returned by other replication API methods, and this method is an easy means of determining a server&amp;rsquo;s id.
The body of the response is a JSON object with the attribute serverId. The server id is returned as a string.
Responses 200 OK is returned if the request was executed successfully.
405 Method Not Allowed is returned when an invalid HTTP method is used.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interface for WAL access</title><link>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/write-ahead-log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.10/develop/http-api/replication/write-ahead-log/</guid><description>The WAL Access API is used to facilitate faster and more reliable asynchronous replication. The API offers access to the write-ahead log or operations log of the ArangoDB server. As a public API, it is only supported to access these REST endpoints on a single-server instance. While these APIs are also available on DB-Server instances, accessing them as a user is not supported. This API replaces some of the APIs in /_api/replication.</description></item></channel></rss>