<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Interface on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/</link><description>Recent content in Web Interface on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dashboard</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/dashboard/</guid><description>The Dashboard section provides statistics which are polled regularly from the ArangoDB server.
There is a different interface for Cluster deployments.
Statistics:
Requests per second Request types Number of client connections Transfer size Transfer size (distribution) Average request time Average request time (distribution) System Resources:
Number of threads Memory Virtual size Major page faults Used CPU time Metrics:
Various server metrics, see Monitoring</description></item><item><title>Cluster</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/cluster/</guid><description>The web interface differs for cluster deployments and single-server instances. Instead of a single Dashboard, there is a Cluster and a Nodes section.
Furthermore, the Replication and Logs section are not available. You can access the logs of individual Coordinators and DB-Servers via the Nodes section.
Cluster The Cluster section displays statistics about the general cluster performance.
Statistics:
Available and missing Coordinators Available and missing DB-Servers Memory usage (percent) Current connections Data (bytes) HTTP (bytes) Average request time (seconds) Distribution:</description></item><item><title>Collections</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/collections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/collections/</guid><description>The collections section displays all available collections. From here you can create new collections and jump into a collection for details (click on a collection tile).
Functions:
Create collections Filter by collection properties Show collection details (click row) Information:
Collection name Collection type Collection source (system or custom) Collection status Collection There are four view categories:
Content:
Create a document Delete a document Filter documents Download documents Upload documents Indexes:</description></item><item><title>Document</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/document/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/document/</guid><description>The document section offers a editor which let you edit documents and edges of a collection.
Functions:
Edit document Save document Delete document Switch between Tree/Code - Mode Create a new document Information:
Displays: _id, _rev, _key properties</description></item><item><title>Query View</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/queries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/queries/</guid><description>The query view offers you three different subviews:
Editor Running Queries Slow Query History AQL Query Editor The web interface offers a AQL Query Editor:
The editor is split into two parts, the query editor pane and the pane for bind variables and query options.
The left pane is your regular query input field, where you can edit and then execute or explain your queries. By default, the entered bind variables will automatically be recognized and shown in the bind variables table in the right pane, where you can easily edit them.</description></item><item><title>Graphs in the web interface</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/graphs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/graphs/</guid><description>The Graphs section of the web interface lists the named graphs stored in ArangoDB (EnterpriseGraphs, SmartGraphs, SatelliteGraphs, General Graphs) and lets you create new named graphs as well as view and edit the settings of existing named graphs. It also provides a viewer facility for visualizing subsets of a graph or an entire graph.
Create a named graph In the Graphs section, click the first card with the label Add Graph.</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/services/</guid><description>The services section displays all installed Foxx applications. You can create new services or go into a detailed view of a chosen service.
Create Service There are four different possibilities to create a new service:
Create service via zip file Create service via github repository Create service via official ArangoDB store Create a blank service from scratch Service View This section offers several information about a specific service.
There are four view categories:</description></item><item><title>Managing Users in the Web Interface</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/users/</guid><description>ArangoDB users are globally stored in the _system database and can only be managed while logged on to this database. There you can find the Users section.
General Select a user to bring up the General tab with the username, name and active status, as well as options to delete the user or change the password.
Permissions Select a user and go to the Permissions tab. You will see a list of databases and their corresponding database access level for that user.</description></item><item><title>Logs</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/logs/</guid><description>The logs section displays all available log entries. Log entries are filterable by their log level types.
Functions:
Filter log entries by log level (all, info, error, warning, debug) Information:
Loglevel Date Message</description></item></channel></rss>