<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Components on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/</link><description>Recent content in Components on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArangoDB Server</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/arangodb-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/arangodb-server/</guid><description>The ArangoDB server is the core component of ArangoDB. The executable file to run it is named arangod. The d stands for daemon. A daemon is a long-running background process that answers requests for services.
The server process serves the various client connections to the server via the TCP/HTTP protocol. It also provides a web interface.
arangod can run in different modes for a variety of setups like single server and clusters.</description></item><item><title>Web Interface</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/web-interface/</guid><description>The ArangoDB server (arangod) comes with a built-in web interface for administration. It lets you manage databases, collections, documents, users, graphs and more. You can also run and explain queries in a convenient way. Statistics and server status are provided as well.
The web interface (also referred to as Web UI, frontend or Aardvark) can be accessed with a browser under the URL http://localhost:8529 with default server settings.</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/components/tools/</guid><description>A full ArangoDB installation package contains the ArangoDB server (arangod) as well as the following client tools:
Executable name Brief description arangosh ArangoDB shell. A client that implements a read-eval-print loop (REPL) and provides functions to access and administrate the ArangoDB server. arangodb ArangoDB Starter for easy deployment of ArangoDB instances. arangodump Tool to create backups of an ArangoDB database. arangorestore Tool to load backups back into an ArangoDB database. arangobackup Tool to perform hot backup operations on an ArangoDB installation.</description></item></channel></rss>