<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install with Docker</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/docker/</guid><description>The recommended way of using ArangoDB is via ArangoDB Docker images with, for instance, Docker Desktop&amp;nbsp;.
You can choose one of the following:
arangodb official Docker images&amp;nbsp;, verified and published by Docker. arangodb/arangodb Docker images&amp;nbsp;, maintained and directly published by ArangoDB on a regular basis. Check also the following resources:
Manually starting a stand-alone instance via Docker Manually starting an Active Failover deployment via Docker Manually starting a Cluster via Docker Start an ArangoDB instance In order to start an ArangoDB instance, run:</description></item><item><title>Installing ArangoDB on Linux</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/linux/</guid><description>You can install ArangoDB on most common Linux distributions. The basic installation steps are:
Visit the official Download&amp;nbsp; page of the ArangoDB web site and choose between Community and Enterprise Edition.
Click the logo of the distribution that matches your operating system. If you use Linux Mint, click Ubuntu or Debian.
You can choose between different installation methods and packages:
distribution-dependent installation packages (.rpm, .deb) tar packages (tar.gz archives) installation via a package manager Installation and tar packages: You may verify the integrity of a download by comparing the SHA256 hash listed on the website with the hash of the file.</description></item><item><title>Installing ArangoDB on macOS</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/macos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/macos/</guid><description>You can use ArangoDB on macOS with Docker images and run the client tools using tar.gz archives.
Starting from version 3.10.0, ArangoDB has native support for the ARM architecture and can run on Apple silicon (e.g. M1 chips). Running production environments on macOS is not supported. Starting from version 3.11.0, ArangoDB Server binaries for macOS are not provided anymore. Docker The recommended way of using ArangoDB on macOS is to use the ArangoDB Docker images&amp;nbsp; with, for instance, Docker Desktop&amp;nbsp;.</description></item><item><title>Installing ArangoDB on Windows</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/windows/</guid><description>You can use ArangoDB on Windows (64-bit) in different ways:
Docker image Automated, using an installation wizard (&amp;ldquo;installer&amp;rdquo;) attended (GUI) unattended (command line) Manually, using a ZIP archive Visit the official Download&amp;nbsp; page of the ArangoDB web site.
You may verify the download by comparing the SHA256 hash listed on the website to the hash of the file. For example, you can run openssl sha256 &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; or certutil -hashfile &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; sha256 in a terminal.</description></item><item><title>Compiling ArangoDB from Source</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/compiling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/compiling/</guid><description>ArangoDB can be compiled directly from source. It will compile on most Linux and macOS systems, as well as on Windows.
We assume that you use the GNU C/C++ compiler or clang/clang++ to compile the source. ArangoDB has been tested with these compilers, but should be able to compile with any Posix-compliant, C++14-enabled compiler. For our Windows builds we use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Visual C++ 2017 compiler.
By default, cloning the GitHub repository will checkout the devel branch.</description></item><item><title>Uninstallation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/uninstallation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/installation/uninstallation/</guid><description>Uninstallation depends on the method used to install ArangoDB, and on the operating system in use, and typically consists of the following high-level steps:
If an installation package is used:
Uninstallation of the ArangoDB package, which may or may not remove the database directory and the configuration files in addition to the ArangoDB binaries, depending on how the uninstallation process is started and on the operating system in use. Optional removal of the leftover files (database directory and/or configuration files) If a tar.</description></item></channel></rss>