<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ArangoDB Starter Administration on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/</link><description>Recent content in ArangoDB Starter Administration on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArangoDB Starter Removal Procedure</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/removal-procedure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/removal-procedure/</guid><description>Do not apply this procedure to machines that have an Agent on it. This procedure is intended to remove a machine from a cluster that was started with the ArangoDB Starter.
It is possible to run this procedure while the machine is still running or when it has already been removed.
It is not possible to remove machines that have an Agent on it! The Agency needs to remain functional for the cluster to operate.</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Starter Recovery Procedure</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/recovery-procedure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/recovery-procedure/</guid><description>This procedure is intended to recover a cluster that was started with the ArangoDB Starter when a machine of that cluster is broken without the possibility to recover it (e.g. complete hard drive failure). In the procedure is does not matter if a replacement machine uses the old or a new IP address.
To recover from this scenario, you must:
Create a new (replacement) machine with ArangoDB (including Starter) installed. Create a file called RECOVERY in the directory you are going to use as data directory of the Starter (the one that is passed via the option --starter.</description></item></channel></rss>