<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upgrading on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/</link><description>Recent content in Upgrading on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community Edition to Enterprise Edition Upgrade Procedure</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/community-to-enterprise-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/community-to-enterprise-upgrade/</guid><description>While migrating from the Community to the Enterprise Edition is supported, installing directly the Enterprise package over the Community package is not supported. Please see below for the correct migration procedure. Migrating from Enterprise to Community Edition is, in general, not supported. This is because the Community Edition does not include some features, such as SmartGraphs that, if used while the database was running under the Enterprise Edition, do not make easily possible the conversion of some database structures.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading _Starter_ Deployments</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/starter-deployments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/starter-deployments/</guid><description>The ArangoDB Starter supports an automated procedure to perform upgrades, including rolling upgrades of a Cluster setup.
The upgrade procedure of the Starter described in this section can be used to upgrade to a new hotfix, or to perform an upgrade to a new minor version of ArangoDB. Please refer to the Upgrade paths section for detailed information.
Upgrade Scenarios The following four cases are possible:
You have installed via an installation package (e.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Manual Deployments</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/manual-deployments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/manual-deployments/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Downgrading</title><link>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/downgrading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.13/operations/upgrading/downgrading/</guid><description>A direct, in-place downgrade of ArangoDB is not supported. If you have upgraded your ArangoDB package, and then also upgraded your current data directory, it is not supported to downgrade the package and start an older ArangoDB version on a data directory that was upgraded already.
If you are using a standalone ArangoDB server, data directory could have been upgraded automatically during package upgrade. If you are using the Starter to start your ArangoDB, and you have not triggered yet the rolling upgrade, or upgraded it manually, your data directory is (probably) still on the old version, so you should be able to downgrade the binaries in this case.</description></item></channel></rss>