<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/</link><description>Recent content in Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication deployment</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/deployment/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition Deployment steps To deploy all the components needed for Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication (DC2DC), you need to set up the following components:
An ArangoDB cluster in each data center Multiple ArangoSync Masters Multiple ArangoSync Workers Optional: Prometheus and Grafana for monitoring Cluster Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication requires an ArangoDB cluster in both data centers.
Since the Agents are so critical to the availability of both the ArangoDB and the ArangoSync cluster, it is recommended to run Agents on dedicated machines.</description></item><item><title>Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication Administration</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/administration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/administration/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition This section includes information related to the synchronization process of the Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication.
Starting synchronization Once all components of the ArangoSync solution have been deployed and are running properly, ArangoSync will not automatically replicate database structure and content. For that, it is is needed to configure synchronization.
To configure synchronization, you need the following:
The endpoint of the sync master in the target datacenter. The endpoint of the sync master in the source datacenter.</description></item><item><title>DC2DC Replication Operations &amp; Maintenance</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/operations-and-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/operations-and-maintenance/</guid><description>Operations &amp;amp; Maintenance ArangoDB Enterprise Edition ArangoSync is a distributed system with a lot different components. As with any such system, it requires some, but not a lot of operational support.
What means are available to monitor status All of the components of ArangoSync provide means to monitor their status. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find an overview per component.
Sync master &amp;amp; workers: The arangosync servers running as either master or worker, provide:</description></item><item><title>Securing Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/security/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition Firewall settings The components of ArangoSync use (TCP) network connections to communicate with each other. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find an overview of these connections and the TCP ports that should be accessible.
The sync masters must be allowed to connect to the following components within the same datacenter:
ArangoDB Agents and Coordinators (default ports: 8531 and 8529) Sync workers (default port 8729) Additionally the sync masters must be allowed to connect to the sync masters in the other datacenter.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/monitoring/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition This section includes information related to the monitoring of the Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication.
Metrics ArangoSync (master &amp;amp; worker) provide metrics that can be used for monitoring the Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication solution. These metrics are available using the following HTTPS endpoints:
GET /metrics: Provides metrics in a format supported by Prometheus. GET /metrics.json: Provides the same metrics in JSON format. Both endpoints include help information per metrics.
Both endpoints require authentication.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/deploy/arangosync/troubleshooting/</guid><description>ArangoDB Enterprise Edition The Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication is a distributed system with a lot different components. As with any such system, it requires some, but not a lot, of operational support.
This section includes information on how to troubleshoot the Datacenter-to-Datacenter Replication.
What means are available to monitor status All of the components of ArangoSync provide means to monitor their status. Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find an overview per component.
Sync master &amp;amp; workers: The arangosync servers running as either master or worker, provide:</description></item></channel></rss>