<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ArangoDB Architecture on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in ArangoDB Architecture on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The scalability of ArangoDB and its data models</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/scalability/</guid><description>Horizontal and vertical scalability ArangoDB is a distributed database system supporting multiple data models, and can thus be scaled horizontally, that is, by using many servers, typically based on commodity hardware. This approach not only delivers performance as well as capacity improvements, but also achieves resilience by means of replication and automatic fail-over. Furthermore, you can build systems that scale their capacity dynamically up and down automatically according to demand.</description></item><item><title>Sharding</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/data-sharding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/data-sharding/</guid><description>ArangoDB organizes its collection data in shards. Sharding allows to use multiple machines to run a cluster of ArangoDB instances that together constitute a single database system.
Sharding is used to distribute data across physical machines in an ArangoDB Cluster. It is a method to determine the optimal placement of documents on individual DB-Servers.
This enables you to store much more data, since ArangoDB distributes the data automatically to the different servers.</description></item><item><title>Replication</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/architecture/replication/</guid><description>Replication allows you to replicate data onto another machine. It forms the base of all scalability and failover features ArangoDB offers.
ArangoDB uses synchronous replication between the DB-Servers of an ArangoDB Cluster.
Synchronous replication is typically used for mission critical data which must be accessible at all times. Synchronous replication generally stores a copy of a shard&amp;rsquo;s data on another DB-Server and keeps it in sync. Essentially, when storing data after enabling synchronous replication, the Cluster waits for all replicas to write all the data before green-lighting the write operation to the client.</description></item></channel></rss>