<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Administration on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/configuration/</guid><description>The programs and tools shipped in an ArangoDB package can be configured with various startup options.
Startup options you specify on a command line are referred to as command line options:
arangosh --server.database myDB --server.username Jay
The same options can also be set via configuration files, using a slightly different syntax:
server.database = myDB server.username = Jay Or more compact like this:
[server] database = myDB username = Jay There are also commands that are intended for command line usage only, such as ‑‑help and ‑‑version.</description></item><item><title>Telemetrics</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/telemetrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/telemetrics/</guid><description>ArangoDB gathers metrics by default, to identify the primary usage patterns and features, and to measure their adoption rate.
It is important to note that the information collected by ArangoDB is non-personal and purely statistical and helps ArangoDB determine which features are most used, how the general usage model looks like, and whether ArangoDB is configured properly.
This data is anonymous and does not contain any personal information like usernames or IP addresses that could be used to identify a particular user, nor does it contain any content of the documents stored in ArangoDB.</description></item><item><title>Log levels</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/log-levels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/log-levels/</guid><description>The log levels in ArangoDB are, from most to least severe:
FATAL ERROR WARN INFO DEBUG TRACE For each log topic (authentication, cluster, queries, etc.), you can configure the lowest level to log. For example, if you set the log level to ERROR for some log topic, you only get messages of level ERROR and higher (ERROR and FATAL). If you set the log level to INFO, you only get messages of level INFO and higher (INFO, WARN, ERROR, and FATAL).</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Edition License Management</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/license-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/license-management/</guid><description>The Enterprise Edition of ArangoDB requires a license to activate the Enterprise Edition features. How to set a license key and to retrieve information about the current license via the JavaScript API is described below. You can also use an HTTP API.
If you use the ArangoDB Kubernetes Operator, check the kube-arangodb documentation&amp;nbsp; for more details on how to set a license key.
Initial Installation The first installation of any ArangoDB Enterprise Edition instance can be immediately used for testing without restrictions for three hours.</description></item><item><title>Import and Export</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/import-and-export/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/import-and-export/</guid><description>Imports and exports can be done with the tools arangoimport and arangoexport.</description></item><item><title>Managing Users</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/user-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/user-management/</guid><description>Authentication needs to be enabled on the server in order to employ user permissions. Authentication is turned on by default in ArangoDB. You should make sure that it was not turned off manually however. Check the configuration file (normally named /etc/arangodb.conf) and make sure it contains the following line in the [server] section:
authentication = true This will make ArangoDB require authentication for every request (including requests to Foxx apps depending on the option below).</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Starter Administration</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/arangodb-starter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reducing the Memory Footprint of ArangoDB servers</title><link>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/reduce-memory-footprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.11/operations/administration/reduce-memory-footprint/</guid><description>The changes suggested here can be useful to reduce the memory usage of ArangoDB servers, but they can cause side-effects on performance and other aspects. Do not apply any of the changes suggested here before you have tested them in in a development or staging environment. Usually, a database server tries to use all the memory it can get to improve performance by caching or buffering. Therefore, it is important to tell an ArangoDB process how much memory it is allowed to use.</description></item></channel></rss>