<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recommended Resources on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/</link><description>Recent content in Recommended Resources on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is ArangoDB?</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/about-arangodb/</guid><description>ArangoDB combines the analytical power of native graphs with an integrated search engine, JSON support, and a variety of data access patterns via a single, composable query language.
ArangoDB is available in a community and a commercial edition. You can use it for on-premises deployments, as well as a fully managed cloud service, the ArangoGraph Insights Platform.
What are Graphs? Graphs are information networks comprised of nodes and relations.</description></item><item><title>Get Started</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/get-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/get-started/</guid><description>This chapter introduces ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s core concepts and covers the following:
The high-level data organization Its data model (or rather multiple data models) Important terminology used throughout the database system and in this documentation You can also find examples on how to interact with the database system using ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s interactive command-line interface called arangosh.
See How to Interact With ArangoDB to learn more about:
Ways you can use and communicate with ArangoDB servers How to set up and deploy an ArangoDB instance Get data in and out of ArangoDB Back up and restore data in ArangoDB Learn more about ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s data structure and data models.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/concepts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ArangoGraph Insights Platform</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/arangograph/</guid><description>The ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;nbsp;, formerly called Oasis, provides ArangoDB databases as a Service (DBaaS). It enables you to use the entire functionality of an ArangoDB cluster deployment without the need to run or manage the system yourself.
The ArangoGraph Insights Platform&amp;hellip;
runs your databases in data centers of the cloud provider of your choice: Google Cloud Platform (GCP) or Amazon Web Services (AWS). This optimizes performance and reduces cost.
ensures that your databases are always available and healthy by monitoring them 24/7.</description></item><item><title>AQL Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/aql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/aql/</guid><description>AQL is mainly a declarative language, meaning that a query expresses what result should be achieved but not how it should be achieved. AQL aims to be human-readable and therefore uses keywords from the English language. Another design goal of AQL was client independence, meaning that the language and syntax are the same for all clients, no matter what programming language the clients may use. Further design goals of AQL were the support of complex query patterns and the different data models ArangoDB offers.</description></item><item><title>Graphs</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/graphs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/graphs/</guid><description>Graphs are information networks comprised of nodes and relations. Nodes can represent objects, entities, abstract concepts, or ideas. Relations between nodes can represent physical and social connections, temporal and causal relationships, flows of information, energy, and material, interactions and transactions, dependency and hierarchy, as well as similarity and relatedness of any kind.
For example, you can represent people by nodes and their friendships by relations. This lets you form a graph that is a social network in this case.</description></item><item><title>Data Science</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/data-science/</guid><description>ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s Graph Analytics and GraphML capabilities provide various solutions in data science and data analytics. Multiple data science personas within the engineering space can make use of ArangoDB&amp;rsquo;s set of tools and technologies that enable analytics and machine learning on graph data.
ArangoDB, as the foundation for GraphML, comes with the following key features:
Scalable: designed to support true scalability with high performance for enterprise use cases. Simple Ingestion: easy integration in existing data infrastructure with connectors to all leading data processing and data ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Index and Search</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/index-and-search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/index-and-search/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Components</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/components/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Deploy ArangoDB</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/deploy/</guid><description>For installation instructions, please refer to the Installation chapter.
For production deployments, please also carefully check the ArangoDB Production Checklist.
Deployment Modes ArangoDB can be deployed in different configurations, depending on your needs.
Single Instance A Single Instance deployment is the most simple way to get started. Unlike other setups, which require some specific procedures, deploying a stand-alone instance is straightforward and can be started manually or by using the ArangoDB Starter tool.</description></item><item><title>Operations</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/operations/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Develop</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/release-notes/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New For a high level list of changes, please refer to one of the following sections:
What&amp;rsquo;s New in 3.x: 3.12, 3.11, 3.10, 3.9, 3.8, 3.7, 3.6, 3.5, 3.4, 3.3, 3.2, 3.1, 3.0 Changelogs For a detailed list of changes to the ArangoDB core programs and tools, please refer to the version specific changelogs:
Changelogs 3.x: 3.12&amp;nbsp;, 3.11&amp;nbsp;, 3.10&amp;nbsp;, 3.9&amp;nbsp;, 3.8&amp;nbsp;, 3.7&amp;nbsp;, 3.6&amp;nbsp;, 3.5&amp;nbsp;, 3.4&amp;nbsp;, 3.3&amp;nbsp;, 3.2&amp;nbsp;, 3.1&amp;nbsp;, 3.</description></item></channel></rss>