<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Integrations on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/</link><description>Recent content in Integrations on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring Data ArangoDB</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/spring-data-arangodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/spring-data-arangodb/</guid><description>Spring Data provides a consistent interface for accessing various types of data sources. Spring Data ArangoDB implements this for ArangoDB and provides mapping of Java objects to ArangoDB documents (ODM).
Repository&amp;nbsp; Demo without Spring Boot Starter&amp;nbsp; Demo with Spring Boot Starter&amp;nbsp; Reference (version 4) Reference (version 3) JavaDoc&amp;nbsp; Changelog&amp;nbsp; Migration Supported versions Spring Data ArangoDB is compatible with:
all the still supported Spring Boot 3.x versions&amp;nbsp; and related Spring Framework versions all the still supported ArangoDB versions&amp;nbsp; Get started This tutorial is about how to configure Spring Data ArangoDB&amp;nbsp; without using Spring Boot Starter ArangoDB.</description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Starter ArangoDB</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/spring-boot-arangodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/spring-boot-arangodb/</guid><description>Repository&amp;nbsp; Demo&amp;nbsp; Supported versions Spring Boot Starter ArangoDB is compatible with all supported versions of ArangoDB. For more information, see the End-of-life announcements&amp;nbsp;.
This integration has multiple versions released, and each one is compatible with the corresponding versions of Spring Boot, Spring Framework, Spring Data ArangoDB, and ArangoDB Java Driver:
Spring Boot Starter ArangoDB Spring Boot Spring Framework Spring Data ArangoDB ArangoDB Java Driver 3.3-x 3.3 6.1 4.2 7.7 3.</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Datasource for Apache Spark</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/arangodb-datasource-for-apache-spark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/arangodb-datasource-for-apache-spark/</guid><description>ArangoDB Datasource for Apache Spark allows batch reading and writing Spark DataFrame data from and to ArangoDB, by implementing the Spark Data Source V2 API.
Reading tasks are parallelized according to the number of shards of the related ArangoDB collection, and the writing ones - depending on the source DataFrame partitions. The network traffic is load balanced across the available DB Coordinators.
Filter predicates and column selections are pushed down to the DB by dynamically generating AQL queries, which will fetch only the strictly required data, thus saving network and computational resources both on the Spark and the DB side.</description></item><item><title>Kafka Connect ArangoDB Sink Connector</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/kafka-connect-arangodb-sink-connector/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/develop/integrations/kafka-connect-arangodb-sink-connector/</guid><description>Check out the connector demo&amp;nbsp; to learn more about the connector. Supported versions This connector is compatible with:
Kafka 3.4 and higher versions JDK 8 and higher versions ArangoDB 3.11.1 and higher versions Installation Download the Jar file from Maven Central&amp;nbsp; and copy it into one of the directories that are listed in the Kafka Connect worker&amp;rsquo;s plugin.path configuration property. This must be done on each of the installations where Kafka Connect will be run.</description></item></channel></rss>