<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ArangoDB Starter on ArangoDB Documentation</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/</link><description>Recent content in ArangoDB Starter on ArangoDB Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArangoDB Starter Options</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/options/</guid><description>Common options --starter.data-dir=path path is the directory in which all data is stored. (default &amp;ldquo;./&amp;rdquo;)
In the directory, a setup.json file is created, which is used for restarts, as well as a directory for each instance that runs on this machine. Different instances of arangodb must use different data directories.
--starter.join=address Join a cluster with the leader (master) Starter at address address (default &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;). You can also point to any other Starter that is connected to the initial Starter.</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/security/</guid><description>Creating certificates The starter provides commands to create all certificates needed for an ArangoDB deployment.
TLS server certificates To create a certificate used for TLS servers in the keyfile format, you need the public key of the CA (--cacert), the private key of the CA (--cakey) and one or more hostnames (or IP addresses). Then run:
arangodb create tls keyfile \ --cacert=my-tls-ca.crt --cakey=my-tls-ca.key \ --host=&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt; \ --keyfile=my-tls-cert.keyfile Make sure to store the generated keyfile (my-tls-cert.</description></item><item><title>ArangoDB Starter Architecture</title><link>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/3.12/components/tools/arangodb-starter/architecture/</guid><description>What does the Starter do The ArangoDB Starter is a program used to create ArangoDB database deployments on bare-metal (or virtual machines) with ease. It enables you to create everything from a simple Single server instance to a full blown Cluster in under 5 minutes.
The Starter is intended to be used in environments where there is no higher level orchestration system (e.g. Kubernetes) available.
Starter versions The Starter is a separate process in a binary called arangodb.</description></item></channel></rss>